Preliminary Inventory of the Paderewski Testimonial Fund Records, 1911-2005
Hoover Institution Archives
- Early Files (Box 30)
  - California
    - Hollywood Committee
      - 1939 September-1940 May (#15)
    - Pasadena Committee (#16)
    - San Francisco Committee, 1940 (#17)
  - Carrel, M.D., 1940 (#18)
  - Clothing, 1940 (#19)
  - Colorado Committee Corp., 1940 (#20)
  - Commission for Polish Relief, Inc. (#1) (Box 31)
  - Commission for Polish Relief, Inc. - information on forming chapters (#2)
  - Paderewski Fund for Polish Relief (PFPR) - information for the formation of committees (#3)
  - Concerts - suggested, 1940 (#4)
  - Connecticut Committee - General, 1940 (#5)
  - Connecticut New Haven Committee, 1940 (#6)
  - D - General. 1939-1940 (#7)
  - Baron De Ropp's Report, 1940 January (#8)
  - Dinner, 1940 March 18 - speech by Potocki (#9)
  - District of Columbia - Washington Committee, 1940 (#10)
  - E - General, 1939-1940 (#11)
  - F - General (#12)
  - Fennell, Gerald M., 1940 (#13)
  - Form letters (#14)
  - G - General (#15)
  - Georgia - General Committee Corp. (#16)
  - Government Appropriations, 1940 (#17)
  - H - General, 1939-1940 (#18)
  - Herbert Hoover (#19)
  - I - General, 1940 (#20)
  - Inter-office memos (#21)
  - Illinois
    - Chicago Committee (#22)
    - Chicago Musical Arts Club (Mrs. S. V. ?) (#23)
    - Champaign, Urbana, Committee, 1940 (#24)
  - Indiana
    - Indianapolis Committee, 1940 (#25)
    - South Bend Committee, 1940 (#25A)
  - J - General, 1939-1940 (#26)
  - K - General, 1939-1940 (#27)
  - Kellogg, Mrs. V. (personal) (#28)
  - Knights of Columbus, 1940 (#29)
  - Knitting groups, 1940 (#30)
  - L - General, 1939-1940 (#1) (Box 32)
  - Louisiana (New Orleans Committee), 1940 (#2)
  - M - General, 1939-1940 (#3)
  - Dr. Henry N. McCracken, 1940 (#4)
  - Massachusetts
    - Boston Committee, 1940 (#5)
    - Pittsfield Committee, 1940 (#6)
  - Michigan
    - Committees - General, 1940 (#7)
    - Detroit Committee, 1940 (#8)
    - Grand Rapids Committee, 1940 (#9)
  - Minnesota - Duluth Committee (#10)
  - Music dealers and organizations (#11)
  - N - General, 1940 (#12)
  - National Association of Music Merchants (#13)
  - National Committee (#14)
  - National Federation of Music Clubs (#15)
  - National Information Bureau (#16)
  - Nebraska - Omaha Committee (#17)
  - New Jersey
    - Princeton Committee (#18)
    - Sayreville, South Amboy, South River Committees (#19)
    - State Committee - Trenton (#20)
  - New York State
    - General Comm. Corp. (#21)
    - Albany Committee (#22)
  - Ohio - Toledo Committee (#23)
  - P - General, 1940 (#24)
  - Paderewski Welcoming Committee (#25)
  - Old Paderewski Fund folder (circulars) (#1) (Box 33)
  - Guido Pantaleoni, Jr., 1940 May-1941 April (#2)
  - Pennsylvania
    - Erie Committee (#3)
    - Philadelphia Committee (#4)
  - Polish American Council, 1940 (#5)
  - Polish Embassy (WDC), 1939-1940 (#6)
  - Polish Falcons of America, 1940 (#7)
  - Polish film, 1940 (#8)
  - Problem of relief for Poland (#9)
  - R - General (#10)
  - Maximilian B. Rinov, 1940 (#11)
  - Mrs. Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1940 re visit (#12)
  - S - General (#13)
  - St. Regis Meeting
    - 1940 April 22
      - Acceptances (#14)
      - Regrets (#15)
  - St. Regis - other meetings (#16)
  - Speeches (#17)
  - Tennessee Committee (#18)
  - Texas Committee (#19)
  - Mrs. Lawrence Tibbett (#20)
  - U - General, 1940 (#21)
  - U.S. Committee for the Care of European Children (#22)
  - V - General (#23)
  - Vermont Committee - General (#24)
  - Victor Company, 1941 (#25)
  - W - General, 1939-1940 (#26)
  - Washington State Committee - General (#27)
  - Wisconsin Committee - General (#28)
  - X, Y, Z - General (#29)
- Paderewski Hospital (Box 34)
  - Trusteeship (#1)
  - Survey (A. C. Pierson)
    - 1949-1950 (correspondence reports) (#2)
    - 1951 (#3)
  - Inventory (from Pierson) (#4)
  - Pierson's correspondence with Coward and Chance (Deed of Trust) (#5)
  - Board of Trade, London (#6)
  - Coward and Chance - re Steczkowski (#7)
  - Deloitte, Plendor, Griffiths - report on Steczkowski accounts (#8)
  - Sale of hospital equipment (#9)
  - Medical Library (#10)
  - State Department and National War Fund (#11)
  - Paderewski Testimonial Fund - Steczkowski and Pierson correspondence (#12)
  - Depositions as to S. Claims (#13)
  - National City Bank (letters exchanged with London Branch) (#14)
  - Inventory - Dr.Steczkowski, 1952 October (#15)
  - Sale of equipment, 1951 - Mr. Pearson (live bids) (#1) (Box 35)
  - Pierson - Steczkowski correspondence, 1951-1952 (#2)
  - Sale of equipment, 1951 - Mr. Pearson (no bids) (#3)
  - Shipment of equipment, 1950-1951 (#4)
  - Trans-World Surgical Corporation
    - Copy of contract included (#5)
    - Mr. Pierson, 1953 (#6)
    - Contract, 1951 November (#7)
  - Section of photographs of hospital (Paderewski Hospital - Polish School of Medicine) (#8)
  - Circulars (#9)
  - Tributes and letters of thanks (#10)
  - History - General Statement (#11)
  - Paderewski Hospital's Director - Dr. Anthony T. Jurasz, M.D. (photos, testimonial letters) (#1) (Box 36)
  - 1941
    - Correspondence and cables (#2)
    - Sponsors (#3)
    - October 17 - opening ceremonies, speeches (#4)
    - Madame Wilkonska Bed (Chairman, Helena Monsztyn) (#5)
  - 1942 - correspondence and cables (#6)
  - 1943 - correspondence and cables (#7)
  - Dr. Jurasz' visit to US, 1942-1943 (#8)
  - World's Fair Donation, 1943-1944 (#9)
  - Medical Library - Kosciuszko Foundation, 1943 (#10)
  - 1944 - correspondence and cables (#11)
  - 1945 - correspondence and cables
    - January-June (#12)
    - July-December (#13)
    - Mobile Hospital to Poland (#1) (Box 37)
    - Gift of Mobile Chapel (#2)
    - Gifts in kind (#3)
    - Dr. Jurasz' report on German camps (#4)
    - Dr. Jurasz' visit to US, 1945 July 11-29 (#5)
  - 1946
    - Correspondence and cables
      - January-June (#6)
      - July-December (#7)
    - Edinburgh Committee (#8)
    - Mobile Hospital to Poland (#9)
    - Special gift to David Band (#10)
  - Nursery - Remittances, 1943 March-1946 July and accounts, 1944 January 1-1945 October 30 (#11)
  - Student and Staff Special Fund Remittances (#12)
  - 1947 - correspondence and cables (#13)
  - Mitana
    - Polish Trip, 1947 (#14)
    - Paderewski Institute - report on Switzerland (with Prof. W. Koskowski) (#15)
  - Paderewski Institute Plans, etc., 1947 (#16)
  - Protest re removal of hospital, 1947 (#1) (Box 38)
  - 1948 - Steczkowski's letter, 1948 August 17 establishing monthly remittance including salary (#2)
  - 1949 (#3)
  - 1949 - newspaper criticisms re disposal (#4)
  - 1950 (#5)
  - 1951 (#6)
  - 1952 (#7)
  - 1953 (#8)
  - Mr. Gross - correspondence re Paderewski Hospital, 1952-1953 (#9)
  - 1954, 1955, 1956 (#10)
- Paderewski Mobile Hospital (Box 39)
  - Bills of lading (#1)
  - Office of Defense Transportation (#2)
  - Nash - Kelvinator Corp. (#3)
  - Studebaker Export Corp. (#4)
  - Photographs (glossy) (#5)
  - Paderewski Hospital Shipping
    - Atlantic Forwarding Co. (#6)
    - British Ministry of Supply Mission (#7)
    - British War Relief
      - 1945-1946 (#8)
      - 1944 (#9)
      - 1942-1943 (#10)
    - Foreign Economic Administration (#11)
    - Northwestern Storage Warehouse (#12)
    - War Production Board (#13)
    - Shipping list (#14)
  - Refugees of England - N.Y. Office, 1941-1942 (list of instruments and equipment to Paderewski Hospital) (#15)
  - Allies Wing British War Relief Soc. (London, 1940) Mrs. Jack Crawshay, 1941 (#16)
  - Refugees of England - N.Y. Office, 1941-1942 - correspondence (#1) (Box 40)
  - Allies Wing British War Relief
    - 1942-1944 (#2)
    - 1945-1949 (#3)
  - Paderewski Mobile Hospital to Poland, 1945-1948 (UNRRA - Amb. Griffis, American Relief for Poland, National Catholic Welfare Conf., Dr. Jurasz' report, National War Fund) (#4)
  - Translation - Mobile Hospital distribution (Polish Social Service Bureau) (#5)
  - Original Inventory from which translation was made (#6)
  - Paderewski Hospital Mobile Unit - Inventory of Distribution (#7)
  - Paderewski Hospital and purchases (Box 41)
    - Balance requirements (#1)
    - Cambridge Instrument Company (#1A)
    - Collegiate Outfitting Company, 1945 (nurses uniforms) (#2)
    - Cochrane Physicians Supplies, Inc., 1943-1947 (surgical instruments, equipment, etc.) (#3)
    - Cochrane Physicians Supplies - duplicate bills (#4)
    - Colson-Merriam Company, 1944 (food conveyers) (#5)
    - Cornell Linen Company, 1942-1943 (#6)
    - County Surgical Company, Inc., 1942 (equipment) (#7)
    - Drey Hygienic Company, 1942 (#8)
    - Drugs and Books, 1942 (Towns and James - Commons Bros., 1944-1945) (#9)
    - Exercycle Company, 1946 (#10)
    - General Electric Company, 1946 (#11)
    - Frank A. Hall and Sons, 1942-1943 (#12)
    - Hospital Equipment Corporation, `943 (#13)
    - Hospital Supply Company (Watters Laboratories, 1942-1943) (#14)
    - International Silver Company, 1945 (#15)
    - Paderewski Hospital Library (#16)
    - Paderewski Hospital Library
      - Booklists, etc., donors, plates (#17)
      - Renewal magazine subscriptions, 1949-1950 (#1) (Box 42)
    - Maplewood paper mills (#2)
    - Dr. Theodore Meltzer, 1941-1944 - NYC office (#3)
    - Miscellany (motion picture, etc.) (#4)
    - Picker X-Ray Corporation (#5)
    - Remington Rand Inc. (typewriters) (#6)
    - Nathan Straus-Duparquet, Inc. (#7)
    - Superior Linen Company (#8)
    - Tobacco (#9)
    - Ges. Wiegl and Co. (#10)
    - Westinghouse Electric International (#11)
    - Eastside Chevrolet Corporation (Mobile TB-Unit) (#12)
    - Licenses and permits (Mobile TB-Unit) (#13)
    - Packing and shipping (Mobile TB-Unit) (#14)
    - Photographs - glossies (Mobile TB-Unit) (#15)
    - Standard Body and Equipment Corporation (Mobile X-Ray TB-Unit) (#16)
    - Westinghouse Electric International (Mobile TB-Unit) (#17)
  - Second Truck Mobile (Box 43)
    - Architects, 1943-1945 (#1)
    - Chev. Chasses (GMI) (#2)
    - Builders (#3)
    - Payments, etc. (#4)
    - Licenses, etc. (#5)
    - Photos, publicity (#6)
  - Chemical Warfare service (#7)
  - Chief of Engineers (#8)
  - Ordnance Department (#9)
  - Prop. Transfer Orders (#10)
  - Quarter Master Gen (#11)
  - Army Service Forces (#12)
  - Chief Signal Officer (#13)
  - Surgeon General (#14)
  - Transportation Officer (#15)
  - Treas. Department (#16)
  - War Department (#17)
  - British War Relief (shipping), 1944-1946 (#18)
- Paderewski Hospital - new sites (Box 44)
  - General correspondence (#1)
  - Correspondence with foundations, government, etc. (a few cross-indexed) (#2)
  - Catholic orders (some indexed) (#3)
  - Polish organizations (some) (#4)
  - Africa, 1949 (#5)
  - Alaska, 1948-1949 (#5A)
  - Argentina, 1949 (#6)
  - Columbia - Bogota, 1950 (#7)
  - Buffalo, NY, 1949-1950 (#8)
  - Canada
    - Montreal, 1950 (#9)
    - Toronto, 1950-1951 (#10)
  - Brazil, 1948-1950 (#11)
  - Toronto (includes photos), 1947-1949 (#12)
  - Canada
    - (Mr. G. R. Giradin - United Polish Relief Fund of Canada, United Emergency Fund for Britain, 1947-1949) (#13)
    - Miscellaneous sites (#14)
    - War Assets Corporation (Ottawa) (#1) (Box 45)
  - Sisters of the Resurrection Hospital Project (Chicago) (#2)
  - Ecuador (#3)
  - England, 1947-1948 (#4)
  - France, 1947-1949 (#5)
  - Germany (#6)
  - PA. (Hazelton) (#7)
  - India (#8)
  - Jamaica (B.W.I.) (#9)
  - Dr. Jurasz' report, 1948 (#10)
  - Dr. Koskowski's report (France-England) (#11)
  - Korea, 1949-1950 (#12)
  - Bolivia (La Paz), 1950 (#13)
  - Correspondence with Ignatius Nurkiewicz (re new hospital), 1951 (#14)
  - Puerto Rico
    - 1949-1950 (#15)
    - 1948 (#16)
    - Proposed budget (#17)
  - Maine (Quoddy Village) (#18)
  - Switzerland (#19)
  - Turkey (#20)
  - United States, 1949 (#21)
  - Venezuela, 1949 (#22)
  - Virgin Islands, 1947-1951 (#23)
  - Yonkers (#24)
- Paderewski Hospital staff (curriculae) - relocation
  - Chicago, Illinois - Dr. W. F. Kalisz, 1950 (org's cross-indexed) (#25)
  - University of Pennsylvania - Dr. Oscar V. Batson (#26)
  - Alphabetically in folders A through L including the following names (Box 46)
    - Dr. J. B. Dekanski (#5)
    - Dr. K. P. Durkacz (#6)
    - Geo. Fegler (#9)
    - Dr. T. Falkiewicz (#10)
    - Dr. Josef Goldberg (#12)
    - Dr. Stefan Grzybowski (#13)
    - Dr. A. W. Jakubski (#16)
    - Dr. Antoni Jurasz (#16A)
    - Dr. Zenon Kocay (#18)
    - Dr. C. K. Kolodynski (#19)
    - Dr. W. Koskowski (#20)
    - Dr. Marjan Kostowiecki (#21)
    - Dr. K. Kuczynski (#22)
    - Dr. Lucas L. Kulczycki (#23)
  - Alphabetically from M through Z with these particular names (Box 47)
    - Dr. Z. Malkiewicz (#2)
    - Dr. B. Markowski (#3)
    - Dr. Z. Menschik (#4)
    - Dr. Elizabeth Poland (#8)
    - Dr. Jan Ruszkowski (#10)
    - Dr. A. W. Soltysik (#12)
    - Dr. Herbert Staniszewski (#13)
    - Dr. Waclaw Szlichcinski (#14)
    - Dr. Wiktor Tomaszewski (#16)
    - Dr. Bernard Wronski (#20)
    - Dr. Antoni Waden (#21)
    - Dr. W. A. Wielhorski (#22)
  - Relocation of personnel - correspondence with organizations, etc., 1951-1952 (#24)
  - IBID, 1949-1950 (#25)
  - Paderewski Testimonial Fund - Loan Fund (hospital survey) (#26)
  - Dr. Jurasz' lists for Paderewski Hospital staff (#27)
- Bank statements-cancelled checks, 1941 April-1956 (Box 48-54)
- Paderewski Hospital financial statements, 1944-1948 June (Box 55)
- Paderewski Hospital accounts, 1946 (Box 56)
  - vouchers, 1947 January 1-May 14
  - vouchers, 1947 (Box 57)
- London Office accounts
  - 1948-1950
  - Dr. Steczkowski's monthly accounts, 1950 January-1952 August
  - 1950-1952 (Dr. Steczkowski) (Box 58)
- List of books purchased for the Paderewski Hospital Library (card index)
- Acknowledgements of donations received from 1939-1948 (Box 59-70)
- Miscellaneous WWII material (not Paderewski Testimonial Fund) (Box 71)
- Miscellaneous Material
  - Carton 1
    - 3" x 5" card file - key to Paderewski Testimonial Fund files (index)
    - 3" x 5" - 4 drawer file - names of contributors to Paderewski Fund (by states, and Queens, Bronx, NYC, etc.)
  - Carton 2
    - Miscellaneous office ledgers, checkbooks stubs, etc.
- Miscellany (Box 72)
  - "Liberation - Russian Style" (n.s.), London, 1944, 88 pps (trials of women during war in Poland, attempt to locate relatives) (#1)
  - Elaborate ink pad folder with some personal items of Anne Osterberg (secretary - Paderewski Testimonial Fund) (#2)
- Sound Recordings (Phonorecords), 1940 (Record cabinet)
  - Sound recording of Jan Paderewski speech to the U.S., 1940 January 29 (Record cabinet)
    Use copy reference number: 59024_a_0001713
  - Sound recording of NBC Talk: Mr. Mikolojczyk, undated (Record cabinet)
    Use copy reference number: 59024_a_0001778
    Part 3
  - The Armies of Poland in Britain sound recording, 1940 January 29 (Record cabinet)
    Use copy reference number: 59024_a_0002810
    A documentary concerning the lives of Polish soldiers during World War II. Parts 2 and 4
- Incremental Materials (Box 79-85)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.